Guide to the Gerrit Lansing Papers YCAL MSS 469
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Gerrit Lansing papers
1944-2008
1814-2018
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lansing, Gerrit
Burton, Deryk
Irby, Kenneth, 1936-2015
Jonas, Stephen
McGavern, John, 1926-2008
Rattray, David, 1936-1993
YCAL MSS 469
65.81 Linear Feet (83 boxes)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc. on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2011.
Purchased from the estate of Gerrit Y. Lansing on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, 2019.
Gift of Gary Gorczyca, 2020.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Box 81 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 82 (computer media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Biographical / Historical
Gerrit Lansing (1928-2018) was an American poet, editor, and critic. Born in 1928 in Albany, New York, and raised in northern Ohio, he studied at Harvard University and Columbia University. Lansing was a longtime friend and correspondent of poet Charles Olson, with whom he shared an interest in the occult. Lansing was a longtime resident of Gloucester, Massachusetts, where he lived with his partner Deryk Burton and operated occult bookstore Abraxas Books. Lansing edited and published the literary journal Set, and wrote collections of poetry including Heavenly Tree Grows Downward (North Atlantic Books, 1977), Heavenly Tree, Soluble Forest (Talisman House, 1995), and February Sheaf (Pressed Water, 2003).
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Correspondence, 1945-2002. II. Writings, 1944-1998. III. Other papers, 1956-2002. IV. Photographs, circa 1970s, undated. V. Ken Irby papers, 1964-2008. VI. Stephen Jonas papers, 1958-2001. VII. Set records, 1960-1967. VIII. August 2019 acquisition, 1814-2018. IX. January 2020 acquisition, 1939-2003.
Scope and Contents
The collection spans the years 1814-2018 and consists of correspondence, writings, photographs, printed material, and other papers documenting the life and work of poet Gerrit Lansing. Correspondence includes letters from many poets, writers, and other associates, including Deryk Burton, Thomas Meyer, Charles Olson, and Jonathan Williams, as well as members of the Lansing family. Writings include both Lansing's work and writings and broadsides by other poets. The collection includes records relating to the publication of the literary journal Set, as well as writings, correspondence, and other papers relating to poets Kenneth Irby and Stephen Jonas.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors and publishers -- United States; Gay authors; LGBTQ resource; Occultism; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Poets; Born digital; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Rune stones; Burton, Deryk; Irby, Kenneth, 1936-2015; Jonas, Stephen; Lansing family; Lansing, Gerrit; McGavern, John, 1926-2008; Meyer, Thomas, 1947-; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970; Rattray, David, 1936-1993; Williams, Jonathan, 1929-2008
- Correspondence, 1945-2002; 1; 5.42 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Alphabetical correspondence and Family correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of correspondence to Gerrit Lansing from a wide variety of poets, writers, and others, as well as letters between Lansing and other members of the Lansing family. Literary and personal correspondence is organized alphabetically, and notable correspondents include Deryk Burton, Thomas Meyer, Charles Olson, and Jonathan Williams.
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1950-2002
    - Abel, David, 1992-1999 (Box 1)
    - Albon, George, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Alden, Daisy, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Donald, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Alpert, Barry, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Alpert, Stephen, 1997-2000 (Box 1)
    - Anastas, Peter, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Andres, Alan, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Bruce, 1978-1987 (Box 1)
    - Anne, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Arcane, Douglas and Lauren/Draven and Onca, 1992-2002 (Box 1)
    - Auxeméry, Jean-Paul, 1992-1999 (Box 1)
    - Babson, Geraldine, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Baltheim, John, 1984-2001; 2 Folders (Box 1)
    - Barnett, Bill (Box 1)
    - Beckett, Tom and Earel Neikirk, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Behrle, Jim, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Bernstein, Charles, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Berthoff, Robert, 1977-1999 (Box 1)
    - Bialy, Harvey, 1968-2002 (Box 1)
    - Blaser, Robin, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Blatner, Barbara, 1954;1990-1995 (Box 1)
    - Blevins, Richard, 1983-1995 (Box 1)
    - Blitz, Michael, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    - Blood, Linda, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Bob, 1990-2000 (Box 1)
    - Boffey, Peter, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Bonney, Sean, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Boone, Bruce, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Bouchard, Dan, 1997-2001 (Box 1)
    - Boughn, Michael, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Bowen, Robert, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
    - Bowering, George, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Brakhage, Stan, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Buck, Fred, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Burlingame, Mildred, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Burns, Joe, 1961-2002; 2 Folders (Box 1)
    - Burton, Deryk, 1961-1979; 10 Folders (Box 1)
    - Bush, Bill, 1958-1961; 6 Folders (Box 1)
    - Butterick, George, 1967-1983 (Box 1)
    - Byington, Robert, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Byrd, Don, 1979-1999 (Box 1)
    - Carolyn (Box 1)
    - Cassidy, Tom, 1954-1961; 4 Folders (Box 1)
    - Catherine, 1950s (Box 1)
    - Cedrins, Peteris, 1991-2000 (Box 1)
    - Chapin, Michael and Mryiam, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Chapman, Lee, 1978-2001 (Box 1)
    - Chapman, Michael, 1959-1970; 2 Folders (Box 1)
    - Charles, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Claridge, Preston, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Clark, Charlie (Box 1)
    - Clark, J. Wesley, 1976-1987 (Box 1)
    - Clarke, John "Jack", 1963-1991 (Box 1)
    - Clay, Steve, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
    - Cohen, Gerald, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Conrad and Beveridge, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
    - Cooney, Seamus, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Corbett, Bill, 1995-2002 (Box 1)
    - Corman, Cid, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Cortelyou, Irwin F., 1950 (Box 2)
    - Creeley, Robert, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Crozier, Andrew, 1964-1968 (Box 2)
    - D., Billy, 1965-1984 (Box 2)
    - Daedalus (Box 2)
    - Dauagh, Geoff, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Davenport, Guy, 1971-1978 (Box 2)
    - David, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Dawdle (Box 2)
    - de Gruttola, Raffael, 1979-1998 (Box 2)
    - Dempsey, W.J., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Dewdney, Christopher, 1981 (Box 2)
    - di Prima, Diane, 1964-2002; 2 Folders (Box 2)
    - Doane, Timotha, 1988-2000 (Box 2)
    - Donahue, Joe, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Donald, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Dorn, Edward, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    - Dorn, Helene, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
    - Doud, Patrick, 1992-1996 (Box 2)
    - Drach, Tom, 1954-1956; 2 Folders (Box 2)
    - Dunlop, Nancy, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Dunn, J. [Joe?], 1962 (Box 2)
    - Dunn, Michelle, 1985 (Box 2)
    - E., Bob, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Eigner, Larry, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Ellis, Stephen, 1991-1994 (Box 2)
    - Elminster, L., 1998 (Box 2)
    - Elmslie, Kenward, 1951-1999; 4 Folders (Box 2)
    - Eric, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Erica and Michael (Box 2)
    - Eshleman, Clayton, 1964-1999 (Box 2)
    - Etron (Box 2)
    - F., Dan, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - F. Henry, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Faulkner, William, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Feidt, Thorpe, 1985-1996 (Box 2)
    - Ferrini, Vincent, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Foss, Rick, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Foster, Ed, 1994-2000 (Box 2)
    - Foy, Roslyn Reso, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Franco, Michael, 1988-1995 (Box 2)
    - Freeman, Glen (Box 2)
    - Friedmutter, Steven, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Frumkin, Marni and Robert, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Funkhouser, Christopher Thompson, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - G. (Box 2)
    - Gail, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Gansz, David, 1988-1996 (Box 2)
    - Gardner, Drew, 1991; 2 Folders (Box 2)
    - Gay, Reginald, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Gibbons, Robert, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Gibson, G., 1979 (Box 2)
    - Giglio, John, Jr. (Box 2)
    - Glover, Albert, 1972-1993 (Box 2)
    - Godwin, Joscelyn, 1990-1994 (Box 2)
    - Goldstein, Seth, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Gooch, Brad, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Gregor, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Gribble, Harry Wagstaff, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Griddle (Box 2)
    - Grier, Edward F., 1986 (Box 2)
    - Griffin, Howard, 1961-1964 (Box 2)
    - Griffith, E.V., 1968 (Box 2)
    - Griffith, Kyle and Kerry, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Grossinger, Richard, 1970-1984; 2 Folders (Box 2)
    - H., Stephen, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Hammond, John Hays, 1959-1964 (Box 2)
    - Hansen, Christian, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Harding, M. Esther, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Hargrove, M., 1957 (Box 2)
    - Harrington, Curtis, 1953-1968 (Box 2)
    - Harwood, Lee, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Hazel (Box 2)
    - Henly, J.T., 1985 (Box 2)
    - Hickman, Leland, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Hejinian, Lyn, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Henning, Barbara, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Holiday, Billie [?] (Box 2)
    - Hollo, Anselm, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
    - Hough, Lindy, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Howard, 1961-1966 (Box 2)
    - Hoyem, Andrew, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Hubert, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Hubert, George, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Huntington Hardford Foundation, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Hurwitz, Rudie, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Irby, Francisco G., 1988 (Box 2)
    - Isherwood, Christopher, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Ives, Sidney, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Jack, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Jackie (Box 2)
    - Jake, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Jarnot, Lisa, 1998-2002 (Box 2)
    - Jawdat, Nameer Ali, 1954-1998 (Box 2)
    - John, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - Johnston, Robert H., 1996 (Box 2)
    - Jonas, Stephan, 1999 (Box 2)
      Contains correspondence from Aldon L. Nielsen regarding permission to publish poems by Stephan Jonas.
    - Jonathan, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Jones, LeRoi, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Joris, Pierre, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Joyce (Box 2)
    - Jung, C.G., 1957 (Box 2)
    - Kaplan, Philip, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Keeney, Scott, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Joan "Joby", 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Robert, 1961-2001; 15 Folders (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Robert, 1963-1997; 3 Folders (Box 3)
    - Keukyasha, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Kiely, Aaron (Box 3)
    - Killian, Kevin, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
    - King, Donna (Box 3)
    - King, Basil, 1988 (Box 3)
    - King, Martha, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Kinney, Jay, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
    - Kiviat, Erik, 1965 (Box 3)
    - Kramer, Eugene, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Krebbs, Manyard G. [?], 2001 (Box 3)
    - Krista (Box 3)
    - ben Kteis, Aswa, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Kugler, Paul, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Kyger, Joanne, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Lally, Michael, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Laniado, Renee Barbara, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Lansing, Gerrit, 1980s-1990s (Box 3)
    - Lardas, John, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Laycock, Don, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Leland, Kurt, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Lenhart, Gary, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Levi-Strauss, David, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Leyland, Winston, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Lichter, Paul, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Lipsky, Kanta, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Little, Glen and Lois, 1995-2002 (Box 3)
    - Lock, Duane, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Lowell, Jim, 1965-1987 (Box 3)
    - Lyons, Kimberly, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
    - M., Paul, 1962-1966 (Box 3)
    - Magisana, Marc, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Mahoney, Denis (Box 3)
    - Malanga, Gerard, 1964-1979 (Box 3)
    - Malone, Eric and Willa Jarnagin, 1995-2001 (Box 3)
    - Mandel, Tom, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Marcellus, Thomas, 1962 (Box 3)
    - Marius (Box 3)
    - Marlow, Alan, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Martin, Harry, 1956-1984; 6 Folders (Box 3)
    - Maud, Ralph, 1996-1999 (Box 3)
    - McCaffery, Steve, 1978-1993 (Box 3)
    - McClelland, Bruce (Box 3)
    - McGavern, John, 1946-1977; 5 Folders (Box 3)
    - McGonigle, Tom, 1992 (Box 3)
    - McNamara, Steve, 1999 (Box 3)
    - McNaughton, Duncan, 1961-2002 (Box 3)
    - Messerli, Douglas, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Meyer, Thomas, 1967-2000; 3 Folders (Box 3)
    - Michael, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Mikolowski, Ken, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Mitchell, Margaret, 1969 (Box 3)
    - Mlinko, Ange, 1994-2001 (Box 3)
    - Monica, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
    - Moody, Gary, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Moot, Barbara, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Mootz, Mary (Box 3)
    - Moreton, Melissa, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
    - Morrow, Bradford, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Mossin, Andrew, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Movius, Geoffrey and Barbara, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Nick, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Norris, Rob, 1983-1999 (Box 3)
    - Nunnelee, Mark, 1971-2000; 2 Folders (Box 3)
    - O., Jack, 1955-1966 (Box 3)
    - Oakley, Paul, 1961-2000; 2 Folders (Box 3)
    - Olson, Charles, 1959-1999; 3 Folders (Box 3)
    - Owens, Derek, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Parker / Crane, Linda, 1969-2000 (Box 4)
    - Patricia, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Patrick, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Pettet, Simon, 1995-2008 (Box 4)
    - Peyrafitte, Nicole, 2 Folders (Box 4)
    - Podgurski, Robert, 1984-2001; 6 Folders (Box 4)
    - Polk, David, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Porter, Mark, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Powell, Donald, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Powell, Richard, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Pressed Wafer, ephemera (Box 4)
    - Prim, Harley Portwood, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Pruit, Patricia, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Rabinowitz, Jacob, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Radoslovich, Jean, 1964-1985; 2 Folders (Box 4)
    - Raleigh, Bill, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Rasula, Jed, 1985-1999 (Box 4)
    - Rattray, David, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
    - Reese, Marshal and Nora Ligorano, 1980-1999 (Box 4)
    - Regardie, Fancis, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - Rehm, Pam, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Reichard, Scott, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Richard, Derek (Box 4)
    - Robison, Mark (Box 4)
    - Rockett, William, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Rodenwald, Clark, 1975 (Box 4)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome (Box 4)
    - Russ, Emma, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Sam, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Sanders, Ed, 1966-1968 (Box 4)
    - Sander, Lewis, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Sandy, Stephen, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Santucci, James, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Schelling, Andrew, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - Scott, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Sears, Hal, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Selver, Charlotte, 1958 (Box 4)
    - Seth, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
    - Shera, Jesse H., 1962 (Box 4)
    - Shively, Charles, 1973-2004 (Box 4)
    - Shore, Mary, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Sinclair, John, 1964-1966; 2 Folders (Box 4)
    - Sittnick, Phil, 1993-1996 (Box 4)
    - Smith, Dale, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Smith, Pat, 1987-2001 (Box 4)
    - Smith, Harry and Crowley. ephemera, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Snow Boots (Box 4)
    - St. Armand, Barton, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
    - Stein, Charles, 1964-1985 (Box 4)
    - Stephens, Joseph, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Steve (Box 4)
    - Stevens, Dennis, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - Stranz, Helen, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Sutton, James A., 1963 (Box 4)
    - Tally, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Tarn, Nathaniel, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Tejada, Roberto, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Thuell, Billy, 1993-1999 (Box 4)
    - Tillery, Patrick, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Torra, Joe, 1996-2000 (Box 4)
    - Towle, Calvin, 1997 (Box 4)
    - U., Bob, 1955-1967 (Box 4)
    - University Books (Felix Morrow, Kathryn Conroy, and Lyle Stuart), 1966 (Box 4)
    - Valente, Peter, 1996-1999 (Box 4)
    - Vas Dias, Robert, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Vail, Sinbad, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Vidarer, Aaron, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Wagstaff, Christopher, 1988-2002 (Box 4)
    - Wakoski, Diane, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Walley, Gay, 1997-2001 (Box 4)
    - Wane, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Watts, Charles, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Watson, Dorothy, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Weber, Ben, 1960-1974; 3 Folders (Box 4)
    - Weinstein, Norman, 1983-1994 (Box 4)
    - Weir, Cynthia, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Weston, Carol, 1967-1991 (Box 4)
    - Wieners, John, 1966-2002 (Box 4)
    - Wiessner, Karl Heinz, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Wiggins, Henry H., 1955 (Box 4)
    - Wigutow, Warren, 1980-1988 (Box 4)
    - Wilby, Basil, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Wilhelm, James J., 1962-1985 (Box 4)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1960-1996; 2 Folders (Box 4)
    - Williams, Peter K.K., 1993 (Box 4)
    - Willner, Dorothy, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, Peter Lamborn, 1991-2002 (Box 5)
    - Winkfield, Trevor, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Wolfe, Jane (Box 5)
    - Wolfstone, 1950-1952 (Box 5)
    - Wolosoff, Bruce and Margaret, 1989-1993 (Box 5)
    - Yarden, Elie, 1957-1999 (Box 5)
    - Yarden, Nona, 1957-1967 (Box 5)
    - Yorck, Ruth, 1958-1966 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 Folders (Box 5)
      - Jim, 1968 (Box 5)
      - John, 1998-2000 (Box 5)
      - Robert, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Family correspondence, 1945-1970
    - GL to Father, 1970 (Box 5)
    - GL to Mother, 1945-1951; 1953; 1960; 9 Folders (Box 5)
    - Family correspondence, assorted, 3 Folders (Box 5)
    - Lansing genealogy (Box 5)
- Writings, 1944-1998; 2; 3.83 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Gerrit Lansing writings, Writings of others, and Broadsides of others.
  This series consists of writings by Gerrit Lansing, writings of other poets, and broadsides by other poets. Lansing's writings include manuscript and typescript poems, collaborations, college writings, and broadsides.
  - Gerrit Lansing writings, 1945-1998
    - "The Bereft" (Box 15 (Oversize))
    - "A Birth in this World" (Box 6)
    - "Blame" (Box 6)
    - "Blue Saliva, for Joan Kelly" (Box 6)
    - "Breakfast", 1964 (Box 6)
      Published in Hardware Poets Occasional #4, Oct. 1964.
    - "By Darklong River: In Praise of Frederick Tuckerman, 1821-1873" (Box 6)
    - Collaborations, 1952 (Box 6)
      Includes: "Mummy is Precipitating to Eternity", "Kindness is Shining", "Canto 69", "Twelve was Climbing the Enigma", "A Vertebra will be Painfully Crying for Celebration", "The Doctor was Joyfully Pumping for the Infinitesimal", "Three Plus Four", "Lines Written in Elation at the Passing of Daylight Savings Time", "The Temperamental Phonograph", and "Six No Trump".
    - College essay - "The Atomic Boom", 1945 (Box 6)
    - College essay - "The Fundamental Unity of the Bhagavad-Gita", 1948 (Box 6)
    - College essay - "John Reed as a Romantic", 1945 (Box 6)
    - College essay - "Literature in the High School", 1945 (Box 6)
    - College essay - "Meaning and Interpretation in Literature" (Box 6)
    - College essay - "The Tales of Howard Phillips Lovecraft" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "The Abdication of the Heart" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "Dawn and the Birds", 1945 (Box 6)
    - College writing - "Integer Vitae" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "Mad Song" and "Cuchilain" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "The Marvelous Heart" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "Miss Aaronson" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "Sad Cypress" (Box 6)
    - College writing - "Salt of the Earth", 1948 (Box 6)
    - Copies of published poems (Box 6)
    - "An Equinoctiall" (Box 6)
      Published in Ashen Meal 1, 1995.
    - "Exploding the Theory of Possessive Individualism" (Box 6)
    - "The Flavor of Strange Attractors" (Box 6)
    - "The Forest Ranger in Springtime" (Box 6)
    - Gay talk / writing (Box 6)
    - "Going Green in the Fall" (Box 6)
    - "Graffiti, Ancient and Modern" (Box 6)
      Published in Ashen Meal 2, 1996
    - "The Heavenly Tree Grows Downward" (Box 6)
    - Letters to Gloucester Times, 1972; 1984 (Box 6)
    - "Moon Street" (Box 6)
    - Mythes, Rêves et Mystères by Mircea Eliade book review (Box 6)
    - "New-England's Rarities Discovered: in Birds, Beasts, Fishes, Serpents, Plants of that Country by John Josselyn, Gent." (Box 6)
    - Notes and fragments (Box 6)
    - "Notes on Nature and Spirit: With Reference to American Spirit", 1998 (Box 6)
    - "On Her Day" and "A Drink" (Box 6)
    - ""Selected Magical Prose of A.C." (Box 6)
    - "A Toast, to Poesy for Robin Blaser" (Box 6)
    - [Untitled] (Box 6)
    - "The Welcome for Nerval, lw Pendu" (Box 6)
    - "Working in the Lower Red Field", 1969 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Writings of others
    - Arcana, Doug (Box 6)
    - Baker, Robert (Box 6)
    - Barefoot, Thomas (Box 6)
    - Baudoupe (?), David (Box 6)
    - Benney, Sean (Box 6)
    - Bernstein, Charles (Box 6)
    - Bialy, Harvey (Box 6)
    - Black, Noel Anderson (Box 6)
    - Blackburn, Paul (Box 6)
    - Blatner, Barbara (Box 6)
    - Blevins, Richard (Box 6)
    - Bouchard, Dan (Box 6)
    - Brakhage, Jane (Box 6)
    - Bremser, Ray (Box 6)
    - Brodewick, John (Box 6)
    - Burns, Gerald (Box 6)
    - Cassidy, Tom (Box 6)
    - Cedrins, Peteris (Box 6)
    - Clarke, John (Box 6)
    - Console, Cyrus (Box 6)
    - Corbett, Bill (Box 6)
    - Creeley, Robert (Box 6)
    - Czerner-Richardson, Dorota (Box 6)
    - de Nerval, Gerald (Box 6)
    - di Prima, Diane (Box 6)
    - Doane, Timotha (Box 6)
    - Doud, Patrick (Box 6)
    - Duncan, Robert, 3 Folders (Box 6)
    - Elmslie, Kenward (Box 6)
    - Franco, Michael (Box 6)
    - Funkhouser, Chris (Box 6)
    - Gardner, Drew, 1989-1994; 2 Folders (Box 6)
    - Gibbons, Robert (Box 6)
    - Grenier, Bob, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Harry - A Reflection of a Line in Time (Box 6)
    - Hastie, Megan (Box 6)
    - Hennix, Christer (Box 6)
    - Hodgson, Ralph (Box 6)
    - Hollo, Anselm (Box 6)
    - Hough, Linda (Box 6)
    - Jarnagin, Willa (Box 6)
    - Kelly, Robert (Box 6)
    - Killian, Kevin, 2 Folders (Box 6)
    - Killian, Kevin (Box 7)
    - Kiviat, Eric (Box 7)
    - King, Basil (Box 7)
    - King, Brian (Box 7)
    - Lansing, Sarah (Box 7)
    - Lenski, B.A. (Box 7)
    - Lovelace, Richard (Box 7)
    - Lozaw, R. (Box 7)
    - Lucas, Brian (Box 7)
    - Malanga, Gerald (Box 7)
    - Malone, Eric (Box 7)
    - Martin, Harry (Box 7)
    - McNaughton, Duncan (Box 7)
    - Meyer, Thomas (Box 7)
    - Meyrink, Gustav (Box 7)
    - Olson, Charles (Box 7)
    - Parker, Linda (Box 7)
    - Peyrafitte, Nicole (Box 7)
    - Podgurski, Robert, 2 Folders (Box 7)
    - Richards, Derek (Box 7)
    - Ryan, Paul (Box 7)
    - Rucker, Rudy (Box 7)
    - Sawyer-Lucanno, Christopher (Box 7)
    - Shively, Charles (Box 7)
    - Sittnick, Phil (Box 7)
    - Smith, Pat (Box 7)
    - Stein,Charles, 3 Folders (Box 7)
    - Stone, Jon Mitchell (Box 7)
    - Strong, Jonathan (Box 7)
    - Tinell, David (Box 7)
    - Tinkham, Todd (Box 7)
    - Torra, Joe (Box 7)
    - [Unknown], 4 Folders (Box 7)
      Includes an article on Ken Irby and various poems with no known authorship.
    - Wakoski, Diane (Box 7)
    - Webb, Don (Box 7)
    - Weiss, Mark (Box 7)
    - Weston, Carol (Box 7)
    - Wieners, John (Box 7)
    - Williams, Jonathan (Box 7)
  - Broadsides of others, 1944-1998
    - Abel, David. "Near the Mimbres." Salient Seedling Press, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Blevins, Richard. "Yet & Still." Zelot Press, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Byrd, Don. "Spanda, Time is two, A Meeting with Henry James and Herman Melville on State Street, The Second Coming from My Study Window, etc.", 1998 (Box 7)
      Written for Gerrit Lansing's birthday. Signed and inscribed by the author.
    - D8IU6. [Untitled], 1994 (Box 7)
    - Driscoll, Karen - "Poems from Journals" - Oasii: Broadside Series no. 2, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Eshleman, Clayton - "Colis" - inscribed and signed by the author - Black Sparrow Press Broadside - flyer no. 5, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Federman, Raymond - "After Spicer" (Box 7)
    - Fisher, Grant - "In the Circle / Galilee," "A solstice greeting from Grant Fisher & Diane di Prima" - printed at Cranium Press in San Francisco, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Gallo, Peter - "mishap or stutter, admitted.. ." - Oasii: Broadside Series, no. 5, 1944 (Box 7)
    - Irby, Kenneth - "Restless the rain returns.. ." - A Tansy Publication, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Joris, Pierre - "Out/Takes" - 232 of 750 copies - inscribed and signed by the author (Box 7)
    - Logan, R - "Rats & Dogs & Dogs & Rats" (Box 7)
    - McClelland, Bruce - "A Pyramid." 3 of 100 copies. Inscribed and signed by the author (Box 7)
    - Metzger, T.H. - "Wad Rules" - Urania, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Natell, Tom, Charlie Rossiter and Dan Wilcox - "Tree, River, Rock." 2nd edition. 3 Guys from Albany, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Parr, Christopher. "At Walden Pond: Late September Inventory", 1990 (Box 7)
    - Pettet, Simon - "Spleen." 100 copies and signed by the author. Kavyayantra Press and The Harry Smith Print Shop, 1995 (Box 7)